Amarnath Doddi SQL and PL/SQL Developer

Email: amarnathdoddi@gmail.com Mobile: +918828570868

Professional Summary:

3.5 Years of experience in Development and Maintenance of Telecom billing system as SQL and PL/SQL Developer.

Has good knowledge and exposure in designing and developing using defined stored procedures and user defined functions and integration application into packages.

Skilled handling critical application and business validation trigger logic and good exposure in working with cross table validation function business related requirement using cursors and ref-cursors.

I have very good challenges in my experience, in the process of development functions critical logic in developing joins, sub-queries and hierarchical queries in SQL*Plus.

Able to handle any type of requirements in Oracle SQL and PL/SQL.

Have good experience with Collections like PL/SQL Records, PL.SQL Tables and Refcursors in PL/SQL blocks.

Good ability to quickly grasp new concepts and technologies possessing problem solving skill as well as hard working and above all a good team player.

Extensively worked on Telecom billing which includes CCM (Customer Communication Management) and ICCM (Integrated Credit Control Management) which follows SDLC Life cycle for Reliance communications postpaid mobile Billing.

Handling and developing business/customer requirements by using PL/SQL , Sagent DataFlow Plans and integrating them with UAT/PROD , thus having a end to end unit testing after every release cycle.

worked on Enhancements raised by operations, designing and tuning queries, procedures in such a way that everything in future can be configurable by operations team.

Work Experience:

Currently associated as Software Developer with HSL Technologies PVT LTD , Mumbai from November 2013 to till date.

Significant Projects:

Project # 1: Integrated Credit Control Management (ICCM) - Revenue Assurance

Client : Reliance Communications

Duration : Jan 2016 to till date.

Software : Java/J2ee (JDBC, Servlets, JSP), Oracle 10g, Windows

XP. Role :SQL, PL/SQL Developer.

Team Size : 6

Description:

This project involves automation of deciding reliance subscriber's credit limit, usage and his/her bill paying behavior and thus calculating & scheduling the MACD's to be fired. This MACD's involve request to suspension/barring/reactivation of any services and generation of reports which helps that top management to decide on future offers on how to gain the revenue and how to stop the revenue leakage.

This also has an admin portal to provide an ease to customer care executive so that they can easily access, having privilege on any customer's account for his/her query.

Responsibilities:

- Coding of PL/SQL procedures, functions & packages and implementing application logic for every trigger based on time and usage of a subscriber.
- Responsible for any wrong request or failure scenarios hence evolving as a support in bug fixing by revisiting the components.
- Created database objects like tables, views, Sequences, Directories, Synonyms, Stored procedures, functions packages, Cursor, Ref Cursor and Triggers.
- Writing and reviewing technical document specifications with the team for every requirement or enhancement in monthly release.

Project # 2 : Customer Communication Management Wireless / Wire line.

(CCM) Client : Reliance Communications

Duration: Nov 2013 to Jan 2016.

Technologies : Oracle 10g, Sagent Dataflow 6.8, Doc1, Shell scripts, Java.

Role :SQL , PL/SQL, Sagent Dataflow

Developer.

Team Size : 8.

Descriptin:

This project is implemented using PB (Pitney Bowes) CCM suite on RCOM environment/products, which involves print/email/sms/storage communication platform for designing, generating, dispatching, archiving & retrieving customer invoices in detail in this domain of Wireless and Wire line LOBs. Thus also providing an ease to operations in re- pushing for failed emails & archiving invoices to customers.

Responsibilities:

- Analyzing/Designing and developing procedures and functions keeping connectivity of external systems in aspects of downtime and security.
- Tracing out the root cause of any downtime occurrence and giving an immediate hot fix .Thus evolving in and as a production support 24*7 for both Wireless and Wire line.
- Reviewing and tuning the code for every requirement and also coordinating/conducting knowledge transfer with other team members/operations after monthly release cycle.

Educational Qualifications:

B.Tech from Jawaharlal Nehru Technological University

Technical Skills:

• Operating Systems: Windows XP/ Linux.

• Languages: SQL, PL/SQL.

• Databases: Oracle 9i/10g/11g.

• Software Tools: SQL Developer

Personal Details:

Date of birth : 21st Jul, 1990.

Nationality : Indian.

Sex : Male.

Language Known : English, Hindi, Telugu.

Declaration:

I declare that all information given in this is to the best of my knowledge and belief, true and correct.

Date: 25-April-2017

Place: Mumbai Amarnath.D